Xiao Wuyi!
It's Young Master Yao!
Young Master Yao?
He's still breathing.
Where is His Highness?
You're going to the battlefield,
so you deserve the best horse.
It can bring you home.
Xiao Wuyi!
Your Highness!
I'll accept your Black Iron Sword.
Yaoyao,
you said you've been learning
to say goodbye your whole life.
So have I.
My parents are gone.
My homeland is lost.
A name and a mission were
forced upon me.
Living in the world,
I got to understand its ways,
yet failing the grace.
What I gained in my life is what I sought.
Yet it is somehow not what I sought.
There is neither anyone to blame
nor anywhere to direct my hatred.
The way of heaven is ruthless.
Blood drenched the Central Plains.
Women and children were reduced to dust.
Though I'm merely a human being,
I'm willing to be the backbone
to rebuild the nation anew.
Yaoyao,
since you've made your promise,
no matter who tries
to take you away in the future,
I will never let you go again.
But 3 months is too short.
How about 3 years?
Can't you just say you'll try harder
to stay alive?
Okay.
Xiao Wuyi!
[Key to the Phoenix Heart]
[Episode 28]
[Three years later, First Year of Hong]
Is that the end?
What about Xiao Wuyi?
Is he dead or alive?
Did the Xiao family really harm
the An and Lu families back then?
Did we win the battle at Dingfeng Slope?
We won, of course!
If not,
why would His Majesty re-establish
Chang County in the northwest?
That's right.
The Xiao family has even
drafted a confession letter.
It couldn't be fake, could it?
Exactly! In the battle at Dingfeng Slope,
our Ye's 40,000 Beifu soldiers
confronted
Northern Qin's 100,000 soldiers
and completely routed Northern Qin.
In this battle, they not only wiped out
the main force of the Northern Qin army
but also allowed 100,000 Ye citizens
to return home safely.
With the Eagle King dead,
the little emperor of Northern Qin was
wary of his meritorious officials,
causing chaos at the imperial court.
And our Ye's Beifu soldiers,
after Prince Qi's...
No,
after His Majesty's Beifu Reform,
they've made an army
of elite soldiers and generals,
with the soldiers
and the people of one mind.
This is all thanks to His Majesty.
All thanks to His Majesty?
I remember the Beifu Reform
was first proposed by Xiao Wuyi, right?
In the battle at Dingfeng Slope,
were it not for him who risked his life,
how could we've held off
the Eagle King's main force?
Were it not for His Majesty's support,
could Xiao Wuyi have
carried out this reform?
-He's right.
-Indeed.
If His Majesty hadn't led the troops
and united the soldiers,
Xiao Wuyi would've
died for nothing.
Stop talking nonsense!
That's not right.
Back then,
were it not for Young Lord Xiao's support,
His Majesty
wouldn't have secured
his position as Regent.
It's all in the past.
Nowadays, His Majesty
works day and night diligently,
promotes talents from poor backgrounds,
and abolishes harsh laws.
His Majesty has the aura of a wise ruler.
Anyway,
is Xiao Wuyi dead or not?
To explain it,
we have to talk about
the firearms
used on the battlefield that day,
the caltrop fireballs!
Looks like it's time for me
to return to Jiankang.
Lady Yu,
your son
didn't come to the clinic with you today?
He set up
a trap at school today,
splashing slops all over his teacher.
The teacher made him stay to copy texts.
Teenage boys always like making trouble.
Yeah,
I'm wondering who he takes after,
tinkering with mechanisms every day.
His father, his teacher, and I
are not like that.
Really?
[Zhengtong Bookstore]
Lady He.
Here in the academy,
I'm only a teacher.
Greetings, Ms. He.
Today we are studying the Announcement
of Duke Shao from the Book of Documents.
Have you looked through it?
Yes, we have.
I don't have a copy of the Announcement
of Duke Shao due to poverty.
This bookstore now belongs to me.
It stores the He family's book collection.
Starting today,
you can borrow and copy books as you like.
I will only charge for ink and paper.
Thank you, Ms. He.
"I plant beans
beneath the southern hills."
"The weeds flourish,
yet the bean sprouts are sparse."
Couldn't I just have it expedited back
on horseback?
Why did I have to bring it back
to Jiankang in person?
[Li Mao, Emperor of Ye]
The mineral map is a national secret.
How could it be entrusted to others?
These two places are
where the iron mines are.
More mining?
Are we going to war again?
The Northern Qin's young emperor is dead.
Rumor has it he was poisoned to death.
The Eagle King's death
dealt a devastating blow
to the Northern Qin's foundation.
Now their princes are having infighting
and ruling on their own.
They're also facing the invasion
of Rong and Qiang.
It's the perfect time
for us to reclaim the Capital
in one fell swoop.
Do you know that Northern Qin
has put a bounty on your head,
and it's gone up to 1,000 taels of gold
in the black market now?
Because of the caltrop fireballs?
Then let them come and try.
I know your lightness skill is
exceptional now,
and you don't need anyone
to protect you at all.
You even sent Qing Long
and Yan Yue back to Beifu
to be regional commanders.
It's just that
you used to love a lively atmosphere.
Now traveling the world on your own,
don't you feel lonely?
Someone is with me on the same path,
so I have never felt lonely.
I felt something was wrong with you
when we tested
the caltrop fireballs yesterday.
What happened?
There are too many impurities
in the stone fat.
Inhaling it into the lungs when it burns
causes this.
What's more,
the land where the stone fat has burned
will be left completely barren.
I have destroyed the designs
for the caltrop fireball.
The burned land at Dingfeng Slope
back then
could no longer be farmed.
One deterrence is enough.
If you insist on using caltrop fireballs
to fight your way back to the Capital,
you will lose people's support.
Even if you trap me here
in Jiankang Palace,
I still won't help you.
Nobody asked you about this.
Aren't you curious
about the Beifu Commander
for the expedition this time?
It's none of my business.
I appointed Old General Ruan,
from the Beifu Yafu Camp.
Only then did I find out that,
during the Reform,
Xiao Wuyi had been
training the camps to coordinate
to restore the supervisory system.
I suppose that was also when
he started preparing for what
would happen after his death.
He was afraid
that one day when he was gone,
the sharp blade of Beifu
would hurt Ye instead.
So he was trying
to create a Beifu Army
that would still fight
for the people of Ye
even without Xiao Wuyi.
The one I sent
to supervise Beifu this time
is my most trusted
Imperial Guard Commander.
He used to be a member of Beifu, too.
He was injured on the battlefield,
and I saved him.
Then we became sworn brothers.
I trust him
even more than I trusted Wuyi back then.
I was still willing
to deliver this map today
because if Xiao Wuyi were still alive,
he'd definitely want me to come in person.
He always wanted to see Ye reclaim
its lost territory, including the Capital,
with his own eyes.
As for what you plan to do with the Beifu
and who you plan to use to replace him,
I don't care at all.
Your Majesty,
you've forgotten him.
The world has forgotten him.
But I haven't,
and I never will.
Jiankang is way too cold.
I will never come back here again.
She's still so hot-tempered.
Where on earth is the Guangyang Gate?
Which way should I go?
Who's there?
Who are you?
The Consort of the Heir of Prince Jing'an.
His Majesty invited me over.
Why don't you go ask him?
I wouldn't dare.
Greetings, Your Highness.
How do I get to the Guangyang Gate?
Acting mysterious.
Dare you go fight on a real battlefield?
Commander, what's wrong?
I'm fine.
It's an old wound.
Have you forgotten
what the miraculous doctor said?
Your body won't allow you
to practice martial arts.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Rise now.
Given your physical condition,
if you want to live long,
you must rest well. Yet you insisted
on going to the Northern Border.
I've agreed to it.
But I only allow you
to be a military supervisor.
If you insist on going to the battlefield,
I will issue an imperial edict
to get you back immediately.
Yes, Your Majesty.
The Consort of the Heir of Prince Jing'an
came to the palace today.
I heard you ran into each other
on the palace path.
If I want to bring her into my harem,
what do you think?
I think...
Never mind.
She has deep affection
for her husband.
I am the Emperor.
I can find any kind of beauty
in the future.
Why limit myself to one person?
Your main purpose
in going to the Northern Border this time
is to mine the mountains.
If you have any problems,
ask the Heir's Consort.
Your Majesty, I remember you once said
that she owns the map
and caltrop fireballs.
Are you truly going to let her
leave Jiankang?
Do you have any better ideas?
Why not detain her first,
claim it's Northern Qin's doing,
and use it as a valid reason for war?
If I really detain her,
she will blow up my whole Jiankang Palace.
Even if she won't blow it up,
I'm afraid
when a certain someone recalls everything,
he will tear down
this Jiankang Palace, too.
Life and death are
the natural order of things.
He's hurt this badly yet still not dead.
What is it in this world
that he clings to so desperately?
Please save my brother, miraculous doctor.
I heard that you have
the power to bring the dead back to life.
Now, only you can save my brother!
That's not bringing the dead back to life.
That's just because they weren't
truly dead.
Wait!
Doctor!
Wuyi is still breathing right now.
You once promised to save my life 3 times.
Please fulfill your last promise.
If you want me to save him,
he must first be pushed
to the brink of death.
It will require cutting him open.
And even if he survives,
he will lose his memory.
Whether he survives or dies
is up to fate.
I believe God will take pity on him.
Don't worry.
Xie Jiayu will be fine.
And she will never betray Ye.
You are going to the Northern Border.
You still need a weapon that suits you.
Miraculous Craft in Jiankang
can create anything.
You can give it a try.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Miraculous Craft?
Why did I draw this sword?
-Great!
-Bravo!
-Brilliant!
[Miraculous Craft]
Is the manager here?
The manager is not here.
You can tell me if you have any needs.
I heard that your workshop
can forge any kind of weapon
according to the requirements.
"Supervised by the government office.
Honest with all customers."
This is very exquisite.
Please take a look.
This is not bad.
Right?
Okay.
Come to pick it up in 3 months.
It takes that long?
I'm leaving soon.
Can I talk to your manager in person?
The manager doesn't meet people.
This is a fixed rule.
It's the same for everyone.
If you can't wait,
you'd better not wait.
[Black Iron Sword]
Who is your manager?
The manager of our shop is
the Grand Master
of Beifu Directorate of Military Equipment
as well as the Consort
of the Heir of Prince Jing'an.
The Consort of the Heir of Prince Jing'an?
How much is the deposit?
No deposit is needed. Our manager said
she'll cover the cost
of materials
if we fail to forge any items.
What if I'm not in Jiankang
when it's done?
Don't worry. Our Miraculous Craft
has branches in both Ye and Northern Qin.
Take your receipt
and claim it at the nearest branch.
In a month,
the Ye Xing caravan
guarantees on-time delivery
within Ye's territory.
Cash on delivery.
Here is your receipt.
Prayer tree.
Yin-Yang Tree
Xiao Wuyi,
could it be that you're actually not dead?
Listen to my analysis.
Firstly,
I didn't even see your body.
Maybe you felt that
being Xiao Wuyi in this life was
too exhausting,
so you wanted to take a rest
and found a place to hide.
When you are well rested,
you will come back to me.
Doesn't that make sense?
Secondly,
you promised me
you would come back.
You have accomplished
everything else.
Xiao Wuyi is always a man of his word.
You couldn't break
your promise on this one,
right?
Why does she feel
so familiar to me?
Why am I feeling an inexplicable heartache
and crying?
But even if you broke your promise,
when we meet in heaven in the future,
I will still forgive you.
You had such a hard,
tiring life.
So I won't blame you for wanting
to rest early.
What do you think?
Am I so generous?
You were lucky
to have me as your wife.
Xiao Wuyi,
I miss you.
I promised you my eternal love.
If you can hear me,
just turn into the wind
or the rain
and meet me in my dreams.
My wish came true so soon?
The younger generation is getting worse.
Go back and practice more
if you want to catch me.
♪ Weave our devotion
into a melody of two hearts ♪
♪ Mirror a gaze of stars and moon ♪
♪ Forever illuminate each other's nights ♪
Are you okay?
Thank you.
♪ The truest, most profound affection ♪
♪ An eternal vow ♪
If this is all he's got,
♪ To be each other's forever ♪
how dare he want to replace Xiao Wuyi?
Hold on...
♪ You enter my dreams,
permeating the crevices of my heart ♪
♪ Every inch of longing ♪
♪ Tugs at unspeakable fantasies ♪
♪ Know that your heart is my heart ♪
♪ Cherishing each other ♪
♪ We will never be alone ♪
♪ In the endless stream of time ♪
♪ My life's every wish is for you ♪
♪ All the sweet nothings in the world
fall short ♪
♪ As time flows gently ♪
♪ Hold each other and seal our vows ♪
♪ Whatever the path ♪
♪ I just want to be with you
for all time ♪
-Xiao Wuyi and Xie Jiayu,
♪ A lifelong promise ♪
-pledge the eternal love.
♪ My life's every moment is for you ♪
♪ After all of it ♪
♪ May all your dreams be realized ♪
♪ Just you and me ♪
♪ From dawn to dusk, year after year ♪
♪ Hand in hand, let's experience
the bittersweet flavors of earthly life ♪
Come take a look.
Freshly steamed buns and stuffed buns.
Look.
They're freshly made and hot.
Really delicious.
Nanxing! Nanxing!
I think I just saw the Heir's Consort.
There's no way.
Her Ladyship was in Cangwu County
when she wrote me last time.
But...
As you also know,
both Jiankang
and the Northern Border
are places of heartbreak for Her Ladyship.
Now, Her Ladyship
prefers to stay in warm places.
But just now...
Mr. Jing.
Did you record the accounts wrong again?
No way.
The inventory and the numbers don't match.
Come with me.
I'll go take a look. Let's go.
[Black Iron Sword]
This is
the Black Iron Sword.
My Lady!
This is the Black Iron Sword
I forged for Xiao Wuyi.
Where is the person who wanted this sword?
When did he or she come?
H-He came this morning.
What did he look like?
What kind of clothes was he in?
He wore
an Imperial Guard uniform
and a scary mask.
The one I sent
to supervise Beifu this time
is my most trusted
Imperial Guard Commander.
He used to be a member of Beifu, too.
He was injured on the battlefield,
and I saved him.
Then we became sworn brothers.
[Xuanzheng Hall]
Xiao Wuyi is not dead, right?
Where is he?
What on earth happened?
You may leave.
Understood.
Xiao Wuyi,
let me be your strongest support.
You and I
will walk the same path.
Xiao Wuyi,
♪ A dying memory glimmers low ♪
I don't just want
to walk the same path as you.
I want to be
♪ You appear, but I can't hold you so ♪
together with you forever.
♪ Time itself comes to a sudden halt ♪
♪ So desolate ♪
♪ I traded obsession for this loss ♪
♪ If I could lay my heart bare and cross ♪
♪ Would you once more have pity on me ♪
Do you admit defeat?
♪ If the heavens should change
and fate tear me apart ♪
♪ Yet still cannot undo one beat
of my heart's art ♪
♪ I've traveled so far—
the day I find you again ♪
Jiayu!
♪ I fear you might have forgotten me ♪
Xiao Wuyi, let go of me!
♪ I fear no doom of endless karmic pain ♪
Grand Tutor.
♪ Only that you drift far from my side ♪
♪ Apart from you,
the world is an endless night ♪
♪ Even if my beating heart
wears thin and fades ♪
♪ I'd choose this fate
till death's final line ♪
♪ I only hope the mortal lands ♪
♪ Can grant our wishes ♪
Xiao Wuyi!
Give Yaoyao back to me.
♪ Through endless night,
let heaven and earth fall apart ♪
Xiao Wuyi!
♪ I'd bid farewell to every worldly part ♪
Xiao Wuyi,
husband and wife share the same fate.
I only want you to live.
♪ Just to gaze upon you one last time ♪
Having you by my side,
I, Xiao Wuyi, have no regrets in my life.
♪ A dying memory glimmers low ♪
There was wind in the valley
♪ You appear, but I can't hold you so ♪
from a karst cave underground.
When Xiao Wuyi was badly injured,
♪ Time itself comes to a sudden halt ♪
he happened to fall into the cave.
A dead end turned into a way of survival.
♪ So desolate ♪
However,
♪ I traded obsession for this loss ♪
it was too late when we found him.
♪ If I could lay my heart bare and cross ♪
He was barely breathing.
♪ Would you once more have pity on me ♪
You were physically and mentally exhausted
from searching for him,
with a persistent fever.
You were so sick and barely hanging on.
How could I possibly tell you?
Also, that miraculous doctor's
treatment method
was too eerie and terrifying.
Neither Xiao Yao nor I had much hope.
Instead of letting you know
that he died
from having his chest and skull opened,
I thought
he would prefer you to believe
that he died a hero.
No.
I asked him to cling to life for me.
I made him hold his last breath for me.
Even if he couldn't hold on in the end,
I still wouldn't blame him.
When exactly did he wake up?
Three months ago,
he returned to Jiankang,
and I immediately wrote to Xiao Yao.
With Hongzhou's flood season approaching,
he couldn't return
due to canal construction.
Later, he told me that,
since Wuyi survived,
it was fine to meet him later.
He asked me to find you quickly.
But I knew you didn't want to hear
any news from Jiankang.
So I sent a message
through Miraculous Craft.
In the end,
you still didn't come back.
If the little emperor of Northern Qin
hadn't happened to die,
finally giving you a reason to return,
I really would have had to send someone
to get you back.
The mask...
What's with the mask?
Xiao Wuyi has lost
all his martial arts skills now,
yet he insists on going
to the Northern Border.
A resurrected
Xiao Wuyi without memories—
how would the Northern Qin's spies
deal with him?
Many people in the army know Xiao Wuyi.
I don't want to see
any accidents happen before he
remembers everything.
Yaoyao,
you are his consort
and his wife.
The road ahead is
yours to decide.
Mao.
Thank you.
It's Xiao Wuyi.
May Lejun be healthy and happy.
May Mao and I have our wishes
come true year after year.
Thank you, sir!
♪ Hear the heartbeat by my side ♪
♪ Like your rush of passion toward me ♪
♪ A toast to our romantic encounter ♪
The Beifu Army shall forge ahead bravely
and be unstoppable!
♪ I am here only for you ♪
♪ Even though I know
tremendous danger lies ahead ♪
♪ If you could fill the empty spaces
in my memories ♪
Yaoyao,
♪ Only you would stay with me ♪
no matter who tries
to take you away in the future,
♪ My heartbeat will never fade ♪
I will never let you go again.
♪ If I could ask for one blessing ♪
♪ With all the longing I hold ♪
♪ It leads me back to you again ♪
♪ With you as my way,
no distance is too far ♪
♪ The wishes left unsaid ♪
♪ A love I can't let go ♪
Whether you achieve great success
in the future
♪ A red thread woven by fate ♪
or are cursed by the masses,
I will always be by your side.
♪ Love carries longing through time ♪
I, Xie Jiayu, always keep my word.
♪ To make it come true ♪
♪ If I could ask for one blessing ♪
♪ With all the longing I hold ♪
♪ It leads me back to you again ♪
♪ With you as my way,
no distance is too far ♪
♪ The wishes left unsaid ♪
♪ A love I can't let go ♪
♪ A red thread woven by fate ♪
♪ Love carries longing through time ♪
♪ To make it come true ♪
Xiao Wuyi!
♪ Let me dash toward where you are ♪
♪ To seek out my own sanctuary ♪
♪ Life hurries by, yet you alone ♪
♪ Illuminate me
with your blazing radiance ♪
♪ Let me burn with courage
as I forge ahead ♪
♪ Your hand in my hand ♪
♪ Our love knows no bounds
of time or space ♪
♪ Two hearts together
until the end of time ♪
I came back a bit late.
You won't blame me, will you?
No, I won't.
It was so hard to snatch a life back
from hell.
When I got this under the prayer tree,
I only had one thought in my mind.
"I must go to the Northern Border.
Someone is waiting for me there.
I must not break my promise."
Xie Jiayu,
You've promised me eternal love
under the prayer tree.
You can't go back on your word.
I will never betray you
and will never regret it.
♪ Let me burn with courage
as I forge ahead ♪
♪ Your hand in my hand ♪
♪ Our love knows no bounds
of time or space ♪
♪ Two hearts together
until the end of time ♪
You pinched me.
Are you trying to hurt your husband?
Rest assured, it's not a dream.
You mean
the child the wet nurse
brought into Prince Qi's Mansion
was dead long ago?
Who was the one
they later replaced him with?
The wet nurse is dead.
Her husband said
they didn't swap him at all.
The child was born weak.
He passed away in a month,
even before they
could swap him.
The wet nurse worried
that if Grand Tutor Xie found out
and punished her,
her whole family would be killed.
So she lied to the Grand Tutor
that the child had been swapped,
but it was actually
still the original one.
The Grand Tutor's son
was gone long ago.
What's more,
I found that Prince Qi and his wife
really loved each other.
The other children were
all born to Prince Qi's Consort.
Only the youngest son was
born to a concubine.
However,
he was raised under the name
of Prince Qi's Consort.
Then the Grand Tutor and Prince Qi...
Doesn't that mean the Grand Tutor
has been living
in an illusion his whole life?
Should we tell him?
What difference does it make
whether we tell him or not?